<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<translation>
<paragraph>
        These selected sentences to help you enlarge your Malay vocabulary are taken from Malaysian newspapers such as Utusan Malaysia and Berita Harian and also online news services Malaysiakini and Bernama this year (2025). I have done something similar in 2011.  <hyperlink href="http://pgoh13.free.fr/mycourse2/malay_sentences_archive1.php" text="Click to go.">Click to go.</hyperlink>
        If you don't agree with my translation, it's ok. It is always possible to translate the same text differently. My translation is more with students in mind. Thus I would translate "laman sesawang bersifat lucah" as "websites of a pornographic nature" instead of "pornographic websites". More sentences will be added so do come back from time to time. - pgoh13 (19/02/2025)
</paragraph>

<sentence>
    <malay>Amalan setiap agama perlu dihormati dan tidak boleh dijadikan bahan persendaan dalam apa jua bentuk, kata Ketua Pengarah Jabatan Kemajuan Islam (JAKIM).</malay>
    <english>The practice of every religion must be respected and should not be turned into a laughing matter in any form whatsoever, said the Director-General of the Islamic Development Department (JAKIM).</english>
  </sentence>
<sentence>
    <malay>Sejumlah lima juta murid memulakan sesi persekohan baharu semalam dan hari ini di seluruh negara.</malay>
    <english>A total of five million pupils began the new academic session yesterday and today throughout the country.</english>
  </sentence>
  <sentence>
    <malay>Sekolah sesi petang yang mempunyai murid dan guru beragama Islam akan menamatkan sesi persekolahan seawal pukul 5.30 petang.</malay>
    <english>Afternoon session schools having Muslim pupils and teachers will end their school session as early as 5.30 in the evening.</english>
  </sentence>
<sentence>
    <malay>Bahasa Melayu, sebagai satu daripada bahasa terbesar di Asia Tenggara, memainkan peranan penting dalam membentuk identiti dan budaya serantau.</malay>
    <english>The Malay language, as one of the largest languages ​​in Southeast Asia, plays an important role in shaping the identity and culture of the region.</english>
  </sentence>
<sentence>
    <malay>Rakyat Malaysia di luar negara khususnya golongan profesional, diminta berfikiran terbuka agar tidak terperangkap dengan pemikiran lama dan sentiasa mencari peluang bagi memperkembangkan potensi diri.</malay>
    <english>Malaysian citizens living abroad, especially those in the professional group, have been asked to be open-minded so as not to be trapped into old-fashioned thinking and to always seek opportunities to develop their full potentiality.</english>
</sentence>
<sentence>
    <malay>Mangsa sempat memberhentikan kenderaan rapat ke besi penghadang, namun tidak dapat keluar menyebabkan mangsa terperangkap dan rentung di dalam kereta</malay>
    <english>The victim managed to stop the vehicle close to the iron railing, but was unable to get out, causing the victim to be trapped and burnt in the car.</english>
  </sentence>
<sentence>
    <malay>Penyanyi tersohor Datuk Seri Siti Nurhaliza membuat permohonan maaf dan mengakui khilaf kerana mempromosikan produk berasaskan nikotin dalam media sosial miliknya, baru-baru ini.</malay>
    <english>The famous singer Datuk Seri Siti Nurhaliza, has apologised and admitted her error in promoting nicotine-based products on her social media account recently.</english>
  </sentence>
<sentence>
    <malay>Sejumlah 3,670 laman sesawang bersifat lucah disekat dari 2022 sehingga 15 Feb lepas, kata Menteri Komunikasi Fahmi Fadzil.</malay>
    <english>A total of 3,670 websites of a pornographic nature has been blocked from 2022 to this Feb 15 said the Minister of Communications Fahmi Fadzil.</english>
  </sentence>
<sentence>
    <malay>Institut Penyelidikan dan Kemajuan Pertanian (Mardi) mendapati kira-kira 50 peratus daripada 5,000 sampel beras import yang dirampas pihak berkuasa telah dicampur beras putih tempatan.</malay>
    <english>The Agricultural Research and Development Institute (Mardi) found that about 50 percent of the 5,000 samples of imported rice seized by the authorities had been mixed with local white rice.</english>
  </sentence>
<sentence>
    <malay>Seorang wanita dan teman lelakinya didakwa di Mahkamah Tinggi Singapura semalam, kerana mendera kanak-kanak berusia empat tahun sehingga mengakibatkan kematian.</malay>
    <english>A woman and her boyfriend were charged in the Singapore High Court yesterday for abusing a four-year-old child to the extent of causing her death.</english>
  </sentence>
<sentence>
    <malay>Penjaga gol buang masa akan dihukum. Di bawah peraturan baru itu, jika penjaga gol memegang bola lebih daripada lapan saat, pasukan lawan akan diberikan sepakan sudut.</malay>
    <english>Time-wasting goalkeepers will be penalized. Under the new rule, if the goalkeeper holds the ball for more than eight seconds, the opposing team will be awarded a corner kick.</english>
  </sentence>

</translation>

